<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Schools on CODATA-RDA Schools of Research Data Science</title>
    <link>http://something-fresh.org/schools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Schools on CODATA-RDA Schools of Research Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://something-fresh.org/schools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/schools/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/schools/history/</guid>
      <description>The School’s Progress 
The first of the schools ran in August 2016 at the International Centre for Theoretical Physics (ICTP) in Trieste, Italy. It was a huge success, delivering the school to 67 students from over 30 countries. The second school, also based at ICTP, in July 2017 was a similar success, with an additional advanced school in the week following it.

Pictures from the First School
[Day 2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/schools/motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/schools/motivation/</guid>
      <description>Why the Schools? 
The ever-increasing volume and variety of data being generated impacts academia and the private sector. Contemporary research and evidence-based decision making cannot be done effectively without a range of data-related skills, such as, but not limited to, the principles and practice of Open Science, research data management and curation, data platforms and infrastructures implementation, data analysis, statistics, visualisation and modelling techniques, software development, and annotation. We define ‘Research Data Science’ as the ensemble of these skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducing the School</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/schools/reproducing-the-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/schools/reproducing-the-school/</guid>
      <description>We have been putting in place mechanisms to ensure that the schools are as pedagogically effective as possible and that they can be easily reproduced elsewhere. To achieve this, we invite students who attended previous schools to take part as helpers in later schools. Through this approach, such students can become more involved and ultimately be involved in running instances of schools in their region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testimonials</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/schools/testimonials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/schools/testimonials/</guid>
      <description>I was lucky to join the school as a student last year, and to return back as helper this year. I think it was nice to live the experience twice but with different flavors:)
Ola Karrar (@ZeinOla) - Trieste 2017

They are amazing! Not just as #DataScientist but they are tremendous human beings! Muchas gracias @Fichulina #DataSaoPaulo17
Juliano van Melis (@juliano_melis) - Sao Paulo 2017

Thanks to CODATA-RDA Summer school, I hv learnt a lot from #machinelearning to #ethics and met beautiful people plus talk about Kenya with a Kenyan-born @simonhodson99 (executive director, CODATA) It was a pleasure meeting everyone at #DataTrieste18</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Schools</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/schools/upcoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/schools/upcoming/</guid>
      <description>2020 Schools 
 #DataTrieste 2020, ICTP, Trieste, 5-16 August 2020 #DataSaoPaulo 2020, CODATA-RDA School of Research Data Science, ICTP, São Paulo, 3-14 December 2020  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>