<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Get-involveds on CODATA-RDA Schools of Research Data Science</title>
    <link>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Get-involveds on CODATA-RDA Schools of Research Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Helper or an Instructor</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/become-an-instructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/become-an-instructor/</guid>
      <description>We are always interested in individuals willing to volunteer to act as an instructor or helper at one of our schools. Please contact us with a short description of your background, what type of courses could you teach or help on and why you are interestedimo taking part&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CODATA-RDA Research Data Science Summer Schools Requirements of hosts</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/become-a-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/become-a-host/</guid>
      <description>Venue 
Hosts are required to provide a venue for the School, keeping in mind that a good venue is crucial to establishing a positive learning environment. Some things to consider include:
 Tables arranged so participants can watch the instructor, use their laptops, and talk with their peers. Fold up desks are usually not a good choice. Tables should be arranged so helpers and instructors can easily mingle around the room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsor the Initiative</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/become-a-supporter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/become-a-supporter/</guid>
      <description>Please help us take the next steps towards expanding the programme and providing regional schools to ‘spread the message’ and achieve our vision of a global network of short courses providing foundational and advanced data skills. We invite sponsorship which will cover the costs of providing instructors for the next Trieste school as well as bursaries for students from LMICs. Sponsorship of the schools have the opportunity to support and meet researchers who may look for careers in your industry or will go on in the longer term to make decisions on purchasing products and services that you deliver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under Construction</title>
      <link>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/become-a-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://something-fresh.org/get-involved/become-a-helper/</guid>
      <description>Comming Soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>